A Guide to the Papers of the Blackwell Family, 1839-1900
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Blackwell Family 1839-1900
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-143-b
This collection consists of 15 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Mrs. Frances J. Hubbard of Charlottesville, Virginia, on 1 December 1977.
Scope and Content
The papers of the Blackwell Family, of Warrenton, Fauquier County, Virginia, consist of 15 items, ca. 1839-1848, primarily letters written to Elizabeth Blackwell Edmonds Blackwell by members of her family. Octavia Edmonds Blackwell Chilton and Elizabeth Miller Blackwell Edmonds, two of Elizabeth Blackwell's daughters, moved with their husbands, John J. Chilton and James Henry Edmonds, to Missouri. Frances Jance Blackwell, another daughter, remained at home, and James De Ruyter Blackwell, a son, also settled near Warrenton. Sarah Buckner, a cousin of Elizabeth Blackwell, lived with a number of her relations.
The letters from the family members who moved to Missouri provide insights into the emotional and physical hardships involved in such emigration.
Arrangement
The items in this collection are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Octavia [Edmonds Blackwell Chilton] and E[lizabeth] E[dmonds] to Frances Jane Blackwell 1839 Jul 8
- John M. Fosless to Elias Edmonds, Sr. 1840 Apr 25
- Sarah Buckner to Elizabeth Blackwell 1841 Apr 5
- James H[enry] Edmonds to Elizabeth Blackwell 1842 Apr 3
- J[ames] H[enry] Edmonds and E[lizabeth] V. E[dmonds] to Betsey Blackwell 1842 Sep 27
- S[arah] T. Buckner to Betsey Blackwell 1843 Jul 1
- Sarah [Buckner] to Betsey Blackwell 1843 Nov 28
- Octavia [Edmonds Blackwell Chilton] to Elizabeth Blackwell 1844 Sep 14
- Octavia [Edmonds Blackwell Chilton] to Elizabeth Blackwell 1845 Feb 28
- Octavia [Edmonds Blackwell Chilton] to Elizabeth Blackwell 1848 Feb 22
- James D[eRuyter] Blackwell to William S. Clarke, bill for tobacco n.y. Mar 27-Dec 2
- Octavia E[dmonds] B[lackwell] Chilton to Elizabeth Blackwell n.y. Jun 12
- Octavia [Edmonds Blackwell Chilton] to Frances Jane Blackwell n.y. Jun 22
- Sarah T. Buckner to Betsy Blackwell n.y. Jun 30
- Sarah Buckner to E[lizabeth] Blackwell n.y. Nov 22